"The Adventures of Fran"...?
I wonder if it's like The Adventures of Niké?
It's not just that the name
is the same as Miss Fran's--
I feel like the face here looks like her, too...
As I looked at that book,
I remembered a country
I stopped by six months before.
It was a big country, far away from here--
It was called Royal Celesteria.
"Royal Celesteria"
Oh?
The mages are doing tricks
for everyone to enjoy.
It's wonderful.
Put your hands together!
"Royal Magic Academy"...
I didn't know they had a place like this...
I wonder if it's okay to go in?
Probably not, right...?
But... I'll just do it.
Hey!
No trespassers allowed here!
Oh, I'm sorry. You're a witch?
Please excuse my rude behavior.
Don't worry about it.
Well then, please excuse me.
No one is allowed inside without permission.
Not even witches?
Not even witches.
He could've at least let me
look around a little bit...
Anyway, I guess I'll look for a place to stay.
Excuse me!
I wonder if that person
is delivering newspapers?
The mages in this country are...
Um, did you need something?
Hello. You're the Ashen Witch, right?
W-We're students at the Royal Magic Academy.
Are you students from
the school I was at earlier?
What business do you have with me?
U-Um, will you come with us
without asking any questions?
Why should I?
I-I said without asking any questi--
I don't want to.
Why not?
Because I don't want to.
Come on, please?
Just trust me and come with us, please.
No way.
Later.
Huh?!
Hey, guys, let's do this as a team.
Yes, let's catch her together.
Catch me? Why?
Don't take all the glory for yourself!
Speak for yourself!
I don't know what's going on, but...
Hey, wait up!
The Ashen Witch?
P-Please don't run away!
You guys go toward the river.
And you guys go around
from the state guest house!
Found you, Madam Ashen Witch!
Please come with us quietly!
They do have the advantage
of knowing the lay of the land.
They're stubborn.
They're determined, at least.
Very well. In that case,
I'll see this through to the end.
Madam Ashen Witch, I've got you!
Slip.
Huh?!
You should really open your eyes.
Madam Ashen Witch, I've got you!
I-I can't go on...
I-I'm dying...
You should know by now that you
can't catch me even if you try as a group.
Please give up.
--Goodbye.
--Everyone, good work.
M-Ma'am...!
You all had no chance against her, did you?
N-No...
Age doesn't matter.
This is the difference between you and a witch.
Long time no see, Elaina.
Miss Fran...
That was the first time I'd seen
my teacher, Miss Fran, in a few years.
That's it for today's extracurricular lesson.
Please turn in your report tomorrow.
Okay...
Thank you very much...
Oh my, they're all so unsteady on their feet.
Maybe you overdid it a little?
Are you saying it's my fault?
It's also my fault.
Are you a teacher at this school, Miss Fran?
Yes. The king asked me to teach here.
Well, let's not stand
around here talking all day.
Let's go inside, Elaina.
As part of their extracurricular lessons,
I told them to bring you to me,
even if they had to use some force.
How did you know that I was in town?
You tried to come into the school, didn't you?
A young witch with
ash-colored hair tried to enter.
She might be a spy from another country!
A spy? He really jumped to conclusions...
I knew right away that it was you.
Then, I just couldn't sit still,
so I used my students to find you.
I thought it'd be hard to find you
myself in such a big country,
and it would be good training for them.
Because going up against
a talented witch is excellent training.
Talented? Well, I guess
you could say that, but...
It was a rare opportunity,
so those kids were happy, too.
I was, too, though.
You've traveled a lot, haven't you?
Yes.
You knew that I was traveling?
Of course.
I heard from your mother.
Huh? You've seen her?
She's very worried about you, you know.
If you're ever near your
hometown, you should go visit.
I'm planning to.
Oh, good.
So, why did you want to
become a traveler, Elaina?
I expect it was because of your mother?
Mom?
Oh, it wasn't?
It was mainly because of a book
called The Adventures of Niké,
which I read when I was young.
Oh, really?
I like that book, too.
My favorite is the last story,
"Foula, the Apprentice Witch."
That's my favorite, too!
It's the story of how the witch, Niké,
takes on the apprentice witch,
Foula, and helps her grow.
In the end, Niké lives in the
countryside as an ordinary woman,
and Foula becomes the new traveler
as the curtain falls on Niké's adventures.
That takes me back.
Huh?
Oh, I was talking about this book.
Just between you and me,
I loved The Adventures of Niké so much
that I wrote a novel as I traveled.
Oh, really.
You don't sound very interested.
No, no, I'm super interested.
And?
After I hit about a hundred pages
of manuscript and went back to read it,
it was so pathetic that it
made me writhe on the floor.
Huh.
I didn't take it out of my travel bag
after that and forgot about it,
but when I was in a certain
country, I sold my bag.
Apparently, that bag was
the bag of a legendary traveler.
A legendary traveler's bag?
It was a cheap bag I'd bought
in a pawnshop, though.
And you left your manuscript in that bag?
How did you know?
Who wouldn't have been able to figure that out?
I remember it occasionally,
and it makes me so embarrassed.
What if someone found
the manuscript and read it?
Miss Fran...
Anyway, it's something I can laugh about now.
So what was the point of telling me about it?
Isn't it obvious?
A lot of things will happen to you
as you continue on your journey.
Someday, I'd like to hear
stories of your fun memories.
Please tell me lots of
stories about your travels.
That's what I wanted to say.
Very well.
Make sure you write in your diary.
You even heard about that from my mom?
I'm looking forward to it--
and so is your mother.
Then, I can't get lazy about writing in it.
Everyone, I believe you met her yesterday,
but let me introduce her again.
This is the Ashen Witch, Elaina.
Um, hello.
She'll be a special guest lecturer today.
Does anyone have any questions for her?
I do!
--Go ahead.
--Do you have a boyfriend? Do you?
I do not. I'm a traveler after all.
Please keep it to questions about magic.
Anyone else?
Um...
Wh-What kind of magic are you good at?
There's isn't one specific type.
From attack magic to transformation magic,
I feel like I have a good handle
on all kinds of magic.
I-I see...
Of all the countries you've ever visited,
which one was your favorite?
I like this one best.
Go ahead.
Are you just trying to flatter us?
I really mean it.
Where are you from?
The Peaceful Country of Robetta.
Is it fun being a traveler?
Yes, very!
I've got a question!
What about your panties? What color--
I instructed the students alongside Miss Fran.
The flow of your magic is going wild.
Calm your mind more and stabilize your magic.
Yes, ma'am!
Hey, stop playing with making
your water into the shape of a sword.
Miss Elaina.
I can't get my water to form a clean ball shape.
What should I do?
You're using too much excess magic.
Try relaxing your power a bit.
Right.
Relax my power...
You relaxed too much.
U-Um... There's something
I'd like you to help me with.
Yes, what is it?
I'm bad at manipulating water...
I can barely lift it up...
What should I do?
Please try doing it now.
Huh?
Um, right...
Oh my.
What should I do?
It looks like you haven't quite
gotten the hang of it yet.
I think you should try practicing
just getting the water out first.
R-Right...
Once you get the water out,
return it to the bucket right away.
And then pull it out again.
Do it like this.
I see.
If you keep practicing this,
I think you'll start to get used to it.
R-Right...
Thank you very much!
No problem.
Excuse me!
Miss Elaina!
Look at this!
Isn't it cool?
It's so cold!
I don't usually teach things to other people,
so with one thing and another,
I had a pretty good time.
This is my favorite spot.
I wanted to show you before
you left again on your journey.
I love this view.
It really is a lovely view.
You'll leave tomorrow morning, right?
Yes.
Too bad.
I think the students really like you.
I'm sure they'll be sad.
It's just unusual to see a young witch.
Of course, I'll be sad, too.
What will the students at the
academy do once they graduate?
They'll work.
Work?
Yes.
Delivering packages, flying people around--
There are many different jobs.
Are the street performers who use
magic also graduates of the academy?
Are they getting paid?
Not very much, but I'm sure they are.
But you know, they're not showcasing
their magic because they want money.
Then why?
It's because they like it.
I mean, you're traveling
because you like it, right?
It's the same.
They're doing it because
they like making people happy.
Because they like it...
There were many times when I felt
that this was a wonderful country.
The beautiful streets, the smiling people...
I was moved every time I saw them.
It could be that the country,
Royal Celesteria, overlapped with my journey.
Speaking of which,
what are some things you like?
Why are you asking that all of a sudden?
I like traveling.
Other than traveling.
I like books?
Anything else?
What's this all about?
Nothing, I was just wondering.
Are you going to give me a parting gift?
Yes, you could say that.
Oh, well, you don't need to do that.
Don't say that. For example,
do you like flowers?
That's a leading question, isn't it?
Well, what about flowers?
Oh, butterflies are nice, too, aren't they?
That's what you like, Miss Fran.
You don't like butterflies?
They're okay.
I see. You like them okay.
So what about flowers, then?
Oh, you're back to flowers.
How about it?
Well, I do like them...
Okay, so you like flowers.
Let's meet at the city gates tomorrow.
She's not here...
I thought, "Miss Fran is probably
planning on giving me flowers."
I'd be happy about that,
but flowers wouldn't last long.
If I saw the same flowers in another country,
I would remember Miss Fran and my time here,
and it might make me sad.
I decided to leave on my journey
without waiting for Miss Fran.
Because then, I might not have
to have those sad feelings later.
Goodbye, Miss Fran.
A flower?
Elaina,
you chose to become a traveler yourself,
so I don't have the right to stop you.
This is all I can do for you.
Miss Fran...
Did it make you happy?
Yes, very!
The students and I are cheering
for you from the bottom of our hearts.
Please do not forget that.
I won't forget you all, either!
G-Goodbye!
Make sure you come back and visit!
We'll wait with open arms!
We'll be waiting for you.
Let us meet again someday.
Until then, goodbye.
Yes!
There is a witch flying over grasslands.
She looks excited, like she's having fun.
What kind of country will she visit next?
What kinds of people will she meet next?
Her heart was filled with hope.
Who was this traveler?
Yes, it was me!
Isn't that a little too cool-looking?
It looks like the next time I see Miss Fran,
I'll have a really
interesting story to tell her.